Having an American Express credit card is
a dream for every credit card lover.
And now you can apply for your favorite credit card
American Express.
You all might be aware that recently American
Express had started accepting applications for its credit cards
and had started accepting applications for only two cards.  The
first is Platinum Charge
Card and the second is Platinum Reserve
Credit Card.  So the Platinum Charge is
a charge card and the Platinum Reserve
is a credit card.  But people want
Platinum Travel Credit Card.  And now you
can get your Platinum Travel Credit Card.  You all must be aware that
Platinum Travel Credit Card is
most famous for its milestone benefits
and American Express is not accepting the application for this credit card.  It's been a
long time since I am
not taking this application.  But now a way has come by which
you can apply for this credit card.
First of all, if you already have an
American Express credit
card.  Like you have this MRCC
or Smart Earn or any other.
Even the Platinum Reserve card.
So now you have the option to
downgrade or upgrade your existing credit card.
So you will be able to upgrade your
MRCC and Smart Earn
to Platinum Travel Credit Card.
It is not a referral link from the link given in the description.  There is a link
you can follow to upgrade.  When will this link
work?  I don't know.  Because this
is an indirect way to get Platinum Travel
Credit Card.  But now it comes to
those people who have to make a fresh application.
Because if you do
n't already have an American Express card,
how will you upgrade to Platinum Travel
?  So the simplest method that has just
surfaced online.  Many users have
reported that this trick worked for them.
So
these people are taking applications for their Platinum Reserve Credit Card.
This is an expensive credit card with a
joining fee of around ₹10,000
and an annual fee.  Plus, taxes are
also levied on it.  So right now you have to apply for this credit
card by visiting their website.
So when your card gets approved
then you have to activate your card
and you should know that American
Express
gives a fee after a few days of card activation, so your
card will get approved first, then after that you
can talk to customer support at
Platinum Travel to downgrade this card.
So, you can indirectly get the Platinum
Travel Credit Card by first
applying for the Platinum Reserve Credit Card.
But this is just a trick.
I am not guaranteeing that this thing will work 100%.
Butt is working for the people.
How long have you been doing this?  I don't know.  It is
working today.  Maybe you can try it today.
Your card should be approved the day after tomorrow and
this process should stop till the next day
and the process of upgrade and downgrade should
end.  So people are just based on
this belief because this
news is spreading on social media that you apply for Platinum Reserve
Credit Card and
after that you have to activate the card without paying any fee.
After that you
can downgrade it to Platinum Travel.  So on this belief you are
applying for a credit card.  So do it at your own
risk.  I also do
not authenticate for this because sometimes
American Express accepts this request
and sometimes it declines saying
that the downgrade option is
not possible.  As I mentioned, the
Platinum Reserve Credit Card
comes with a joining and annual fee of ₹10,000.  And
your Platinum Travel Credit Card
comes with a debit of ₹5,000 plus 18%
GST.  So almost that card costs ₹5,900.
This is why it is famous for its milestone benefits.  Platinum
Travel will first give you ₹1,000 American Express Reward Points
if you spend ₹15,000 within 90 days of your card being issued.
If you spend ₹1.9 lakh within a year using this card,
you will
get ₹1,000 American Express points.
And if your spend touches Rs 4 lakh,
you will get additional ₹25,000
American Express points.  So
you will get ₹15,000 on spending ₹1.9 lakh and
₹25,000 on spending ₹4 lakh. So you spend ₹4 lakh
and here you get ₹0000
American Express Reward Points.
And the base rewards you will get will be there in
which you get one MX point for ₹50.
Additionally, you
also get a Taj voucher worth ₹10,000.  So you spend ₹4
lakh and earn ₹40,00 reward points
as a milestone benefit.   You get a
voucher of ₹10,000 and the base
reward will also be available.  So because of this
you have to spend ₹4 lakh in a year
and you get very good benefits
from this card.  There are
very few exclusions on this card.  That's why
people achieve milestones quickly.
Their method is that they
purchase some products and then sell them.
Like right now, there is a
buzz about gold in the market.  Everyone
buys gold because it will give you milestone benefits even on jewellery.
If you
buy it, you get reward points in return.
So
what you do for free is that you are earning money on gold also.
You will also get free American Express reward points on the money that will increase.  But how
sustainable will it be, not for long.
Due to this the card has also been closed.  And for this
reason, these cards will also be evaluated.  If the
business was becoming so sustainable,
American Express wouldn't stop taking applications.
This card also gives you at-time
domestic airport lunch access two times a
quarter.  So you get all these benefits on this card.
Pay a joining fee of ₹5,900 and the annual fee will also be the same.
So now you have the option to
apply for Platinum Reserve Credit Card first.
If you activate that card.
You have to keep in mind that the RBI
's 30-day time period is
applicable only till you do
not activate your card.  Because if you do
not activate the card then
your card will automatically be cancelled and you will
not have to pay any fee.  But if you
apply for Platinum Reserve Credit Card
and activate it, then now you will have to
pay ₹10,000 plus taxes.  And
if American Express
refuses to accept your application for downgrade, then
brother, you are in trouble.  And even
if you already have a Platinum Travel Credit
Card and you have MRCC or Smart
Earn, you can upgrade your MRCC and
Smart Earn to Platinum Travel.
So, you can
hold two Platinum Travel Credit Cards at a time
and now by achieving the
milestone of ₹44 lakh on both the credit cards,
you can spend around ₹1 lakh and earn
membership rewards from both your cards by spending ₹8 lakh.
I could also
upgrade my MRCC to Platinum Travel.
But I do not need it
because I had taken it through referral card, so
I have to pay an annual fee of ₹1500.  There are
good milestone benefits on this too
and I don't have to spend ₹4 lakhs
because I
don't manage the expenses
just because I have to achieve some milestones
and I need free money.  If I don't
use it, I don't use it.  I
have 40-50 credit cards.  What
milestones will I achieve?  They are lying there,
kept with me.  So if you are
looking for a sustainable option then avoid
this trick.  And if you really
want to get an American Express credit card, you can go for the Platinum Reserve.
And you can apply to downgrade it again at your own risk.  I
hope you liked this video.  One
always wants to keep watching such informative videos.
Do subscribe our channel.
So see you in the next video.  Till then take
care of yourself.  Bye bye.